<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>MATE (Публикации относно Fedora)</title><link>https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/</link><description/><atom:link href="https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/bg/tags/fedora.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><language>bg</language><copyright>Contents © 2021 &lt;a href="mailto:webmaster@mate-desktop.org"&gt;The MATE Team&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-SA"
style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-sa/3.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 06:21:52 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>MATE 1.10 with GTK3 for Fedora 21 and 22</title><link>https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/bg/blog/2015-06-11-mate-1-10-with-gtk3-for-fedora-21-22/</link><dc:creator>Wolfgang Ulbrich</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The MATE Desktop maintainers for Fedora are pleased to announce that experimental
GTK3 builds are available for testing on Fedora 21 and Fedora 22. These GTK3 build
do work but have some minor rendering issues, we'd value your feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Installation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install the repo file and do a &lt;code&gt;yum update&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Fedora 22&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;$ wget https://copr.fedoraproject.org/coprs/raveit65/Mate-GTK3/repo/fedora-22/raveit65-Mate-GTK3-fedora-22.repo
$ sudo cp raveit65-Mate-GTK3-fedora-22.repo /etc/yum.repos.d/
$ sudo yum update
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Fedora 21&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;$ wget https://copr.fedoraproject.org/coprs/raveit65/Mate-GTK3/repo/fedora-21/raveit65-Mate-GTK3-fedora-21.repo
$ sudo cp raveit65-Mate-GTK3-fedora-21.repo /etc/yum.repos.d/
$ sudo yum update
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or use &lt;code&gt;dnf&lt;/code&gt; command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;$ sudo dnf copr &lt;span class="nb"&gt;enable&lt;/span&gt; raveit65/Mate-GTK3
$ sudo dnf update
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Reporting issues&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please use the MATE Desktop issue tracker on GitHub and include 'GTK3 and Fedora'
in subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;https://github.com/mate-desktop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some notes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compiz will only work with &lt;code&gt;emerald&lt;/code&gt; as window-decorator.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not use use a mix of GTK2 packages from Fedora stable and GTK3 packages from the
  repo above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not use the following MATE applications with a GTK3 build of MATE; they aren't ported to GTK3:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mintMenu and MATE Menu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mate-applet-streamer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mate-applet-lockkeys&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mate-applet-softupd&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;caja-terminal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/bg/blog/2015-06-11-mate-1-10-with-gtk3-for-fedora-21-22/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 22:30:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MATE 1.6 released</title><link>https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/bg/blog/2013-04-02-mate-1-6-released/</link><dc:creator>Stefano Karapetsas</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The team is proud to announce the release of MATE Desktop 1.6. This release is
a giant step forward from the 1.4 release. In this release, we have replaced
many deprecated packages and libraries with new technologies available in
GLib. We have also added a lot of new features to MATE. We would like to thank
every MATE contributor and user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="about" src="https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/assets/img/blog/about-mate-1.6.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Main changes in 1.6 are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;systemd &amp;amp; logind support&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for &lt;code&gt;systemd-logind&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;mate-session-manager&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;mate-screensaver&lt;/code&gt;
  and &lt;code&gt;mate-power-manager&lt;/code&gt; (now you can reboot/shutdown without ConsoleKit)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Caja (file manager)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved places sidebar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for new thumbnailers specification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a new frame for thumbnails &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wallpapers are now cached for a better memory management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New connect server dialog from Nautilus 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for freedesktop.org&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;File Manager DBus Interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed back vs parent directory selection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open terminal extension now support opening a remote terminal &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Panel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;--run-dialog&lt;/code&gt; option to open the run dialog window Window list: you can 
  use the mouse middle click button to close a window Workspace switcher: &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added an option to wrap around between workspaces with the mouse wheel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added a simple way for distributions to override the default panel layout
  Unfortunately, due to migration to GSettings, you will lose your current panel layout.
  All other settings will be migrated if you have MateConf 1.4 installed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Marco (window manager)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added option to open new windows on the center of the screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Control center&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added option to enable Marco compositing manager and fast alt-tab in window preferences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set GSettings/GConf metacity theme if compiz or metacity are running&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use same GNOME proxy settings of &lt;code&gt;gsettings-desktop-schemas&lt;/code&gt; package&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Default applications: allow to set default terminal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Atril (document viewer)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added XPS backend &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calc&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated codebase&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added buttons to support inverse trigonomic functions &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notification daemon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added option to &lt;a href="https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/blog/2013-01-20-changes-to-mate-notification-daemon/"&gt;specify which screen to display notifications on&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show always a notification if it has 'expires never' as timeout (also if screensaver is active or there are active fullscreen windows) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Themes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/blog/2013-03-26-new-themes/"&gt;New GTK2/3 themes&lt;/a&gt; (Menta, BlackMATE, GreenLaguna, TraditionalGreen)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added GTK3 support for other GTK2 themes (TraditionalOk, TraditionalOkTest, ContrastHigh) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enabled text preview for text files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added some new icons &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Settings daemon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added support for MPRIS2 to send media keys to media players&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added option to draw the background if Caja is not active&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The daemon is now restarted by &lt;code&gt;mate-session&lt;/code&gt; if it crashes &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Netbook applet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable maximus only when window picker applet is added to the panel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dropped packages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replaced MateConf with GSettings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replaced MateCorba/MateComponent with DBus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replaced MateVfs with GIO/GVFS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replaced &lt;code&gt;libmatenotify&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;code&gt;libnotify&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed &lt;code&gt;libmate&lt;/code&gt; (mate-open replaced with gvfs-open, GSettings schemas moved to mate-desktop package &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed deprecated packages&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;libmateui&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;libmatecanvas&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;libmatecomponentui&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;mate-mime-data&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other improvements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a lot of code deprecations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a lot of bugs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added and improved a lot of translations &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We asked people from distributions that ship MATE what they think about our
Desktop Environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;George Vlahavas&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.salixos.org/"&gt;Salix&lt;/a&gt; founder and project leader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe MATE is a perfect match for Salix. MATE provides us with a familiar
desktop environment that is powerful, solid and fast. Also, the MATE team are
very friendly and a pleasure to work with and this means a lot to us. Thanks for
giving us the choice of sticking with our favourite desktop guys&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clement Lefebvre&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.linuxmint.com/"&gt;Linux Mint&lt;/a&gt; founder and project leader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's extremely important to us that people are happy with their computer. When that
environment we all loved and worked hard to improve since 2006 was
discontinued we weren't happy to let it go and to ask people to migrate to
something new or something different. We worked really hard on making sure our
users could continue to use their computer the way they wanted and we met a
team of like-minded people who had taken the initiative to support that
environment and to develop it even further. Mint and MATE go hand in hand and
the relationship between the teams is excellent. Mint played an important role
in the promotion and backing of MATE and we continue to help with its
development. We're very pleased with MATE, it's exactly what we wanted, it
started where GNOME left off and with each new iteration it keeps getting better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joost Ruis&lt;/strong&gt;, strategy consultant of &lt;a href="https://www.sabayon.org/"&gt;Sabayon&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don't like how upstream forced changes to users and want our users to have
the option to decide what to use. With MATE in our repositories we are certain
our users can always choose what works best for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dan Mashal&lt;/strong&gt;, MATE maintainer in &lt;a href="https://fedoraproject.org/"&gt;Fedora&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since the release of Fedora 15 was released I was extremely unhappy and
frustrated with my desktop experience until I discovered MATE. Now on Fedora I
can finally have a desktop that is sane, stable, fast and most importantly easy
to use. With the hard work the team has done to also patch compiz to work on
the newer releases of Fedora I can now have my Fedora 14 (considered by most to
be the best release of Fedora) experience back with wobbly windows, desktop
cube, animations, and 3d effects. I can't stress how big of a loss this was to many users including
myself. Now with MATE I don't have to worry about what is going to break with
the next Gnome release and what crazy design ideas they are going to have
making me have to relearn a desktop interface every single Fedora release.
With MATE 1.6 I can feel right back at home on my favorite Linux distribution
and get back to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also asked for a comment from the
&lt;a href="https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/blog/2012-12-27-thank-you-first-colo/"&gt;company who donated the server where we host MATE services&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Martin Verges&lt;/strong&gt;, CEO of &lt;a href="https://www.first-colo.net/en/"&gt;FirstColo GmbH&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are really happy to use the MATE Desktop Environment. This way we can keep a clean and well
working desktop without lots of useless and distracting stuff. Until the end
of 2012 our whole company were working with Ubuntu, but with the Unity Desktop
and many other "end user features", we were searching for new ways to get a
desktop, free of software that pretends to make our lives easier. With MATE
Desktop on Debian 7 Wheezy, we found a good working, high performance desktop
that just works as we know it from years. We hope that the MATE Team will keep
our classic Linux Desktop and bring to it new life some with new features, but
with the good workflow kept in hand. So far, they have done great job, and we
hope that soon the Debian Maintainers will add the MATE Desktop to their
mirrors (and of course, that many others will use MATE too!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MATE 1.6 is the result of 8 months of intense development and contains 1800
contributions by 39 people, and more than 150 translators. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/gallery/1.6/"&gt;MATE 1.6 Screenshots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/bg/blog/2013-04-02-mate-1-6-released/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 19:23:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MATE package repository for Fedora</title><link>https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/bg/blog/2012-11-10-mate-package-repository-for-fedora/</link><dc:creator>Steve Zesch</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are now directing users to use the official Fedora package repository now.
For instructions on using this repository please consult &lt;a href="https://wiki.mate-desktop.org/#!pages/download.md#Fedora"&gt;our installation
guide for Fedora&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information about MATE's official inclusion in Fedora, see the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Features/MATE-Desktop"&gt;https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Features/MATE-Desktop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions regarding installing MATE on Fedora then please ask
for help in our &lt;a href="https://web.libera.chat/?#fedora-mate"&gt;#fedora-mate IRC channel&lt;/a&gt;
or for general MATE questions join us in &lt;a href="https://web.libera.chat/?#mate"&gt;#mate IRC channel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/bg/blog/2012-11-10-mate-package-repository-for-fedora/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2012 20:51:28 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>