<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>MATE (Постови о News)</title><link>https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/</link><description/><atom:link href="https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/sr/tags/news.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><language>sr</language><copyright>Contents © 2021 &lt;a href="mailto:webmaster@mate-desktop.org"&gt;The MATE Team&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Creative Commons License BY-SA"
style="border-width:0; margin-bottom:12px;"
src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-sa/3.0/88x31.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 06:26:16 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Упознајте Мејтовог управитеља</title><link>https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/sr/blog/2015-01-28-meet-mates-mastermind/</link><dc:creator>Stefano Karapetsas</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Имао сам срећу да ме позову у 347. епизоду [Линуксове акционе
представе] (https://www.jupiterbroadcasting.com/show/linuxactionshow/) да
мало поразговарамо о Мејтовој радној површи, одакле је потекао и куда иде.
Интервју са мном можете видети у наставку.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OwW9jaVKjSw?start=1945" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Нисам успео да покријем све развојне циљеве Мејта 1.10 доступне у
то време, те вам препоручујем да погледате &lt;a href="https://wiki.mate-desktop.org/#!pages/roadmap.md"&gt;Мејтову мапу пута&lt;/a&gt;
за потпун преглед. Ако бисте имали додатних питања, или бисте
волели да допринесете пројекту, онда се радујемо ћаскању са
вама на &lt;a href="https://web.libera.chat/?#mate"&gt;#мејтовом ИРЦ каналу&lt;/a&gt; или
прегледању ваших &lt;a href="https://github.com/mate-desktop"&gt;захтева за повлачењем на ГитХаб-у&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.jupiterbroadcasting.com"&gt;Јупитерово емитовање&lt;/a&gt; производи велики број
недељних видео емисија и подкастова углавном усмерених на ФЛОСС. Погледајте,
можда ћете наћи нешто што вас занима.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>News</category><guid>https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/sr/blog/2015-01-28-meet-mates-mastermind/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 22:17:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ризнице пакета Дебиана и Убунтуа су уклоњене из „mate-desktop.org“</title><link>https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/sr/blog/2014-09-25-debian-and-ubuntu-repositories-removed/</link><dc:creator>Мартин Вимпрес</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Захваљујући напорима &lt;a href="https://salsa.debian.org/groups/debian-mate-team/-/group_members"&gt;одржаваоца Мејтових пакета за Дебиан&lt;/a&gt;
Мејт 1.8.1 је доступан у Дебиан „Jessie“-у (тестирање) и такође у
&lt;a href="https://backports.debian.org"&gt;Debian backports&lt;/a&gt; за „Wheezy“.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Као резултат Мејта 1.8.1 који погађа ризнице Дебиан тестирања
раније ове године, Мејт 1.8.1 је такође званична архива
за Убунту 14.10 „Utopic Unicorn“. Тим &lt;a href="https://ubuntu-mate.org"&gt;Убунту Мејта&lt;/a&gt;
је недавно направио &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/~ubuntu-mate-dev/+archive/ubuntu/trusty-mate"&gt;ППА Мејта 1.8.1 за Убунту 14.04 „Trusty Tahr“&lt;/a&gt;
на захтев &lt;a href="https://lists.ubuntu.com/archives/technical-board/2014-July/001981.html"&gt;Убунтуовог техничког одбора&lt;/a&gt;
и такође и &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/~ubuntu-mate-dev/+archive/ubuntu/precise-mate"&gt;ППА Мејта 1.8.1 за Убунту 12.04 „Precise Pangolin“&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ако су вам потребни Мејтови пакети за Дебиан и Убунту тада су горње ризнице
пакета званичне ризнице за коришћење.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Уклонили смо ризнице пакета удомљене на „mate-desktop.org“-у 
јер су неки били непотписани а други нису одржавани више месеци.
Стога су, од сада, уклоњене су ризнице пакета Дебиана и Убунтуа
удомљене на „mate-desktop.org“. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Debian</category><category>News</category><category>Ubuntu</category><guid>https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/sr/blog/2014-09-25-debian-and-ubuntu-repositories-removed/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 11:34:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MATE projects accepted for GSoC 2014</title><link>https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/sr/blog/2014-04-28-mate-desktop-gsoc-2014-projects/</link><dc:creator>Martin Wimpress</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After several weeks of review the application and selection period for the 
2014 Google Summer of Code (GSoC) is over. 4,420 students proposed a total of
6,313  projects for this summer. From those, 1,307 students have been accepted
and the MATE Desktop project is one of the 190 Open Source projects that will
be  working with students this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our second year as a GSoC mentor organisation the MATE team received 4
student proposals we were allocated 3 slots for student projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm delighted to introduce our GSoC students for 2014:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avishkar Gupta will be working on adding ePub rendering capabilities to
  Atril, the document viewer of the MATE desktop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Michal Ratajsky will be working on adding GStreamer 1.0 support into the 
  MATE desktop environment in order to replace the dependency on the deprecated 
  GStreamer 0.10 library.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alexander van der Meij will be working on improving Caja extensions so they 
  can be integrated during runtime and also create a single user interface for
  Caja extension configuration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please join me in welcoming these new contributors to the MATE team and wish
them every success with their respective projects for the summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On behalf on the entire MATE team I'd also like to extend our thanks and
gratitude to &lt;a href="https://www.opensuse.org"&gt;openSUSE&lt;/a&gt; who are our GSoC organiser for
2014. They did a fantastic job in helping secure these GSoC placements for the
MATE team that will provide much need development resources to the project.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/sr/blog/2014-04-28-mate-desktop-gsoc-2014-projects/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 06:14:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>galculator is coming to MATE 1.10</title><link>https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/sr/blog/2014-03-17-galculator-is-coming-to-mate/</link><dc:creator>Martin Wimpress</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The MATE team is proud to announce that we are collaborting with the
&lt;a href="http://galculator.mnim.org/"&gt;galculator&lt;/a&gt; team and that galculator
will replace &lt;code&gt;mate-calc&lt;/code&gt; in MATE 1.10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is galculator?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the galculator website:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;galculator is a GTK 2 / GTK 3 based calculator with ordinary
notation/reverse polish notation (RPN), a formula entry mode,
different number bases (DEC, HEX, OCT, BIN) and different units of
angular measure (DEG, RAD, GRAD). It supports quad-precision
floating point and 112-bit binary arithmetic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;galculator's main features include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Algebraic mode, RPN (Reverse Polish Notation), Formula Entry and Paper mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decimal, hexadecimal, octal and binary number base&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Radiant, degree and grad support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic and Scientific Mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User defined constants and functions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trigonometric functions, power, sqare root, natural and common logarithm, inverse and hyperbolic functions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Binary arithmetic of configurable bit length and signedness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quad-precision floating point arithmetic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;112-bit binary arithmetic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy and paste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Available in more than 20 translations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like MATE galculator has a commitmet to GTK2 and GTK3 and is actively
maintained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why ditch mate-calc?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While &lt;code&gt;mate-calc&lt;/code&gt; is functional it lacks many features required of a
modern desktop calcualtor. The MATE team is small with limited resources
and where possible we are attempting to collaborate with projects that
add value to MATE and reduce development burden on the MATE team.
galculator is a perfect fit in this regard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What's in it for the galculator team?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;galculator will remain an entirely independent project but we hope that its 
inclusion in MATE will grow the galculator user base, raise awareness about 
galculator and attract new contributors to their project. To that end the 
MATE team will host the galculator translations as a resource on the
&lt;a href="https://www.transifex.com/organization/mate/dashboard/MATE"&gt;MATE transifex project&lt;/a&gt;.
We are hopeful that the ~300 heroic MATE translators will embrace galculator and
add to the ~20 languages galculator currently supports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;I am a packager. What does this mean for me?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a MATE package maintainer then start creating galculator
packages for your distribution if they do not already exist and add
galculator to your MATE meta packages or package groups. MATE 1.10 is a
way off yet, so you have plenty of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully you undertand our reasoning and can see the mutual advantages
for this partnership. Let us know what you think in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/sr/blog/2014-03-17-galculator-is-coming-to-mate/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 07:38:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MATE Desktop singing the BlueZ</title><link>https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/sr/blog/2014-03-11-mate-desktop-singing-the-bluez/</link><dc:creator>Martin Wimpress</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The MATE team are delighted to announce that we are collaborating with the
&lt;a href="https://github.com/blueman-project/blueman"&gt;Blueman project&lt;/a&gt; and helping to
update Blueman to BlueZ 5.x.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why ditch mate-bluetooth?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;mate-bluetooth&lt;/code&gt; supports BlueZ 4.x which has been discontinued and many
distributions have, or are about to, replace BlueZ 4.x with BlueZ 5.x in their
respective package repositories. Migrating &lt;code&gt;mate-bluetooth&lt;/code&gt; to BlueZ 5.x was
shaping up to be a lot of work and doesn't provide the range of features
available in Blueman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why Blueman? Isn't it dead?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the original Blueman project has stagnated, &lt;a href="https://github.com/cschramm"&gt;Christopher Schramm&lt;/a&gt;
has reignited the development and started porting Blueman to BlueZ 5.x. While
there is also some effort in updating Blueman to support BlueZ 5.x we feel it
will provide a far better Bluetooth interface for MATE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;When will the updated Blueman be ready?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The observant among you may have noticed that the &lt;a href="https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/blog/2014-03-04-mate-1-8-released/"&gt;MATE 1.8 release announcement&lt;/a&gt;
already mentioned that &lt;code&gt;mate-bluetooth&lt;/code&gt; has been replaced with Blueman and the
even more observant will also have noticed that a fresh version of Blueman has
not yet been released. Yeah, we suck! Sorry about that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we acknowledge that we suck, we are actively contributing to the effort of
porting Blueman to BlueZ 5.x and GObject introspection. We are hoping to have it
ready in time for MATE 1.8.1 which is primarily intended as a bug fix
release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Can't you do it faster, damn it?!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes. Anyone familiar with BlueZ 4.x/5.x, dbus, PyGObject and PyGTK is encouraged
to contribute via the &lt;a href="https://github.com/blueman-project/blueman"&gt;Blueman GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/sr/blog/2014-03-11-mate-desktop-singing-the-bluez/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 07:45:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MATE is participating in GSoC 2014</title><link>https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/sr/blog/2014-03-10-mate-desktop-gsoc-2014/</link><dc:creator>Martin Wimpress</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The MATE team are very pleased to announce that we are participatiing in 
&lt;a href="https://www.google-melange.com/archive/"&gt;Google Summer of Code&lt;/a&gt;. We are doing this 
in partnership with our good friends at &lt;a href="https://www.opensuse.org"&gt;openSUSE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;About Google Summer of Code&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Summer of Code (commonly called as GSoC) is a global program that 
offers student developers stipends to write code for various open source 
software projects. GSoC works with many open source, free software, and 
technology-related groups to identify and fund projects over a three month 
period. Since its inception in 2005, the program has brought together over 
7,500 successful student participants from 97 countries and over 7,000 
mentors from over 100 countries worldwide to produce over 50 million lines 
of code. Through Google Summer of Code, accepted student applicants are 
paired with a mentor or mentors from the participating projects, thus 
gaining exposure to real-world software development scenarios and the 
opportunity for employment in areas related to their academic pursuits. In 
turn, the participating projects are able to more easily identify and bring 
in new developers. Best of all, more source code is created and released for 
the use and benefit of all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;For students&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The student application period is open from March 10th 2014 until March 21st 2014.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For assistance in how to apply please read the &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/open-source/gsoc/faq"&gt;Google Summer of Code 2014 
FAQ&lt;/a&gt;. 
If you are a student who wants to contribute to MATE via the openSUSE GSoC 
participation you'll what to check out the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://wiki.mate-desktop.org/pages/gsoc-2014"&gt;MATE Google Summer of Code 2014 Ideas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:GSOC_ideas"&gt;openSUSE Google Summer of Code 2014 Ideas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.opensuse.org/2014/03/04/opensuse-participates-in-gsoc-2014/"&gt;openSUSE participates in GSoC 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short the MATE GSoC project ideas for 2014 are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ePub format support in Atril&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GStreamer-1.0 support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plugin system in Caja&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, the key is to start early and to interact with mentors and the 
community at large. Fixing bugs, submitting pull requests and working on Proof 
of Concepts is a good way to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The GSoC 2014 mentors for MATE are Stefano Karapetsas (&lt;code&gt;stefano-k&lt;/code&gt; on IRC) and 
Martin Wimpress (&lt;code&gt;flexiondotorg&lt;/code&gt; on IRC). The best way to communicate and 
interact with the MATE mentors is via:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://web.libera.chat/?#mate"&gt;#mate IRC channel on Libera Chat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://matrix.to/#/#mate:libera.chat"&gt;#mate:libera.chat Matrix room&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/mate-desktop"&gt;MATE on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to reviewing your applications!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/sr/blog/2014-03-10-mate-desktop-gsoc-2014/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 13:14:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Потребни су доприноси у превођењу Мејта</title><link>https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/sr/blog/2014-02-14-mate-translation-contributions-requested/</link><dc:creator>Martin Wimpress</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Покажите вашу љубав према Мејтовом пројекту на дан заљубљених, затрпајте нас
преводима!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Преводиоци су неопевани јунаци Мејтовог развојног тима и још једном их
позивамо да нам помогну у побољшању пројекта. Мејт 1.7 је у завршном тестирању
и QA и ускоро ће Мејт 1.8 бити припремљен за издавање.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Стога тражимо од вас да проверите стање Мејтових превода које сте
урадили на Трансифексу и да их дорадите „ASAP“.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.transifex.com/projects/p/MATE/"&gt;https://www.transifex.com/projects/p/MATE/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ако још увек нисте члан преводилачког тима али бисте желели да помогнете тада
&lt;a href="https://www.transifex.com/signup/contributor/"&gt;направите слободан налог на Трансифексу&lt;/a&gt;
тако да можете почети да доприносите Мејту, бићемо вам веома захвални!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Тренутно 6 језика има преведеност од 100%, зато хајде да видимо колико их још
може достићи 100% пре него ли изађе Мејт 1.8.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>i18n</category><category>News</category><guid>https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/sr/blog/2014-02-14-mate-translation-contributions-requested/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2014 12:51:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MATE Desktop Roadmap Reshuffle</title><link>https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/sr/blog/2014-02-13-mate-desktop-roadmap-reshuffle/</link><dc:creator>Martin Wimpress</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few days ago &lt;a href="https://github.com/stefano-k"&gt;Stefano Karapetsas&lt;/a&gt; posted an 
announcement on the &lt;code&gt;mate-dev&lt;/code&gt; mailing list outlining the decision to reshuffle
the MATE Desktop roadmap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially GTK3 support for MATE has been pushed back to MATE 1.10 because 
there is still a good deal of work to be done to get it really stable. Therefore
MATE 1.8 will continue to be based GTK2, although GTK3 applications integrate
nicely just as they did in MATE 1.6. The updated roadmap is available on our
wiki:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://wiki.mate-desktop.org/#!pages/roadmap.md"&gt;MATE Roadmap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This decision was made because the current development version of MATE is stable,
incorporates many new features, improvements and bug fixes. We want to get all
that &lt;em&gt;"good stuff"&lt;/em&gt; ™ out to our users so they can benefit from the
advancements we've made sooner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read the original mailing post and follow-up comments below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Split MATE 1.8 roadmap]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The feedback we've had so far about this decision has been positive. What do you
think?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/sr/blog/2014-02-13-mate-desktop-roadmap-reshuffle/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 06:43:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MATE Desktop Mythbusting</title><link>https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/sr/blog/2014-02-05-mate-desktop-mythbusting/</link><dc:creator>Martin Wimpress</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was fortunate enough to be invited on to Episode 26 of the &lt;a href="https://www.jupiterbroadcasting.com/show/linuxun/"&gt;Linux 
Unplugged&lt;/a&gt; podcast to talk a 
little about MATE Desktop and where it is headed. The MATE Mythbusting clip is
embedded below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="640" height="360" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/sRNK9QnnvCo?start=603" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn't able to cover all the development objectives of MATE 1.8 in the time 
available so I recommend you take a look at the &lt;a href="https://wiki.mate-desktop.org/#!pages/roadmap.md"&gt;MATE Roadmap&lt;/a&gt;
for a complete overview. If you should have any additional questions, or would
like to contribute to the the project, then we look for to chatting with you 
in the &lt;a href="https://web.libera.chat/?#mate"&gt;#mate IRC channel&lt;/a&gt; or
reviewing your &lt;a href="https://github.com/mate-desktop"&gt;pull-requests on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.jupiterbroadcasting.com"&gt;Jupiter Broadcasting&lt;/a&gt; produce a number of 
weekly videocasts and podcasts mostly oriented around FLOSS. Take a look, you 
may find something that interests you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/sr/blog/2014-02-05-mate-desktop-mythbusting/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 00:17:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>MATE desktop Live CD</title><link>https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/sr/blog/2014-01-30-mate-desktop-live-cd/</link><dc:creator>Martin Wimpress</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The MATE team have made a Live CD that boots into a full MATE desktop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="alert alert-info"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt; The LiveCD was updated to MATE 1.8 on March 10th 2014.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Live CD was created so that potential new users can evaluate the MATE 
desktop in a non-destructive fashion. The image can be burned to a DVD, 
mounted as an ISO file, or be directly written to a USB stick using a utility 
like &lt;code&gt;dd&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;a href="https://luddites.latenightlinux.com/"&gt;Linux Luddites&lt;/a&gt; beware, &lt;code&gt;unetbootin&lt;/code&gt; is
not supported. You can download it below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;BitTorrent download (recommended)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can spare the bytes, please leave the client open after your download 
is finished, so you can seed it back to others. &lt;em&gt;A web-seed capable client is 
recommended for fastest download speeds.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[matelivecd-14.069.1449.iso.torrent]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;HTTP direct download&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the BitTorrent link above, the Live CD .iso can also be
downloaded via HTTP. Please ensure the downloaded file matches the SHA1
checksum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[matelivecd-14.069.1449.iso] [ ~964MB ]&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SHA1: &lt;code&gt;12b529d17d1ecef39d9b0e1122fb5271e0534c0a&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Compatibility&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Live CD is built using &lt;a href="https://www.archlinux.org"&gt;Arch Linux&lt;/a&gt; and MATE 
1.8. The Live CD is 32-bit so should work on any i686 or x86_64 computer
with at least 512MB RAM. Xorg drivers are included for Intel (&lt;code&gt;i915&lt;/code&gt;),
AMD/ATI (&lt;code&gt;radeon&lt;/code&gt;) and nvidia (&lt;code&gt;nouveau&lt;/code&gt;) with a fall back to VESA.
Drivers for Virtual Box and VMware are also included so that evaluation
using these virtualization solutions is simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All common file systems, including &lt;a href="http://open-zfs.org"&gt;ZFS&lt;/a&gt;, are supported 
and some data recovery and backup tools are included. If you plug in your 
mobile device it will most likely be recognised and you'll be able to access 
the data on it. NetworkManager is included along with all the VPN clients it 
supports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Usernames and passwords&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MATE Desktop Live CD has the following accounts configured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;root&lt;/code&gt; - password is &lt;code&gt;livecd&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;mate&lt;/code&gt; - password is &lt;code&gt;livecd&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;root&lt;/code&gt; account is obviously &lt;code&gt;root&lt;/code&gt;. The &lt;code&gt;mate&lt;/code&gt; account it a regular user 
that has with full password-less &lt;code&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt; rights. The Live CD will auto-login 
using the &lt;code&gt;mate&lt;/code&gt; account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Applications&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Live CD is primarily designed to showcase the MATE desktop, however we've 
included some additional applications that are not part of the MATE desktop in 
order to make the LiveCD a little more useful and enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/"&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt;   - Standalone web browser from mozilla.org&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://gparted.sourceforge.io/"&gt;GParted&lt;/a&gt;   - A Partition Magic clone, frontend to GNU Parted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.berlios.de/software/hardinfo/"&gt;HardInfo&lt;/a&gt;  - A system information and benchmark tool&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://hexchat.github.io/"&gt;HexChat&lt;/a&gt;   - IRC client configured to auto-connect to &lt;a href="https://web.libera.chat/?#mate"&gt;#mate@libera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gnome.org/projects/orca"&gt;Onboard&lt;/a&gt;      - Screen reader for individuals who are blind or visually impaired&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gnome.org/projects/orca"&gt;Orca&lt;/a&gt;      - On-screen keyboard useful for mobility impaired individuals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://pidgin.im/"&gt;Pidgin&lt;/a&gt;    - Multi-protocol instant messaging client&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.xnoise-media-player.com/"&gt;Xnoise&lt;/a&gt;    - Media player with a slick GUI, great speed and lots of features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Creative Commons content&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have bundled the following Creative Commons licensed content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.greenteapress.com/thinkpython/"&gt;Think Python&lt;/a&gt;                        - To read with Atril&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Changing language&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be default the Live CD is configured to use the &lt;code&gt;en_US&lt;/code&gt; locale but if you want 
to activate another language here is how to do it. In the example below, we 
will enable Italian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit &lt;code&gt;/etc/locale.gen&lt;/code&gt; an uncomment your locale, in this case &lt;code&gt;it_IT.UTF-8 UTF-8&lt;/code&gt;
and rebuild the locales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;sudo locale-gen
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit &lt;code&gt;/etc/locale.conf&lt;/code&gt; and change the &lt;code&gt;LANG=&lt;/code&gt; to reflect your locale, in this 
case &lt;code&gt;LANG=it_IT.UTF-8&lt;/code&gt;. Finally restart the display manager and you will be 
logged back into a MATE session using your prefered language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;sudo systemctl restart lightdm
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Linux Action Show Feature&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MATE Desktop LiveCD and MATE itself we featured on the &lt;a href="https://www.jupiterbroadcasting.com/show/linuxactionshow/"&gt;Linux Action 
Show&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a href="https://www.jupiterbroadcasting.com/50842/cubox-linux-review-las-s30e08/"&gt;CuBox 
Linux Review&lt;/a&gt; 
episode. Two clips are embedded below, the first a quick look at the MATE 
Desktop LiveCD the second is a review of the CuBox i4 which is running MATE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;MATE Desktop LiveCD&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;iframe width="640" height="360" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/y4OpjoJiAGE?start=608" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;CuBox i4 Pro Review&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;iframe width="640" height="360" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/y4OpjoJiAGE?start=1925" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope you give the Live CD a test drive and enjoy the speed and simplicity 
the MATE Desktop provides. Once you've taken the MATE Desktop Live CD for a 
spin let us know what you think in the comments or use the Live CD to join us 
in the &lt;a href="https://webchat.freenode.net/?channels=#mate"&gt;#mate IRC channel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://preview.mate-desktop.dev/sr/blog/2014-01-30-mate-desktop-live-cd/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 00:17:32 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>